# Matthew MacLeod Curriculum Vitae

ADDRESS
2F1 / 16 St. Peter's Place
Edinburgh EH3 9PJ
PHONE
+44 (0)7976 121 482
EMAIL
matt@matt-m.co.uk
DATE OF BIRTH
3 October 1985

British

### About me

I am a cross-platform, full-stack web developer with over seven years of commercial experience, and I build complex frameworks and web applications with Ruby on Rails. I use the latest best practices, tools and techniques, with a focus on clean code, maintainability and an excellent user experience for both developers and clients. I also have a comprehensive understanding of a wide range of other web technologies and strategies for integration with external systems.

# Technical skills

Commercial experience **developing**, **deploying and supporting** large-scale commercial Ruby on Rails applications

Extensive knowledge of **application hosting** with Apache, Mongrel, nginx, Passenger, thin and unicorn

**Git/SVN** for source control; **Capistrano** for deployment; **Trac/Trello/Pivotal/ ActiveCollab** for project management

Integration with web services, AWS, Google APIs, MS-SQL/Oracle, REST

Test- and behaviour-driven work using **rspec** and **test\_unit**, some use of **Cucumber** to provide user-facing specs

Running and using CI servers and continuous builds using **Cruise Control** and **Hudson** 

Front-end implementation with (X) HTML, HTML5, CSS2/3, JavaScript and jQuery, JSON and AJAX, Sass and Haml

**MySQL** and **PostgreSQL** admin, management and optimisation

Basic **PHP** development, including **CakePHP**, **Joomla** and **Drupal** 

**Android/iOS** development, including **HTML5**-driven apps using **PhoneGap** 

**Devops**, sysadmin and maintainance of **Linux** & **MacOS** servers

Full familiarity with Unix commandline tools and basic **shell scripting** 

**Linux kernel development** and assembly tuning for embedded systems

## Other skills

Project management, business administration, budget control, team leadership and staff management. Professional experience with media and design packages: Adobe Photoshop, InDesign and Illustrator. Comprehensive print design and production experience with newspapers, magazines, and advertising.

# **Portfolio**

parkcircus.com glasgowfilm.org guitar.co.uk scottishrefugeecouncil.org.uk theskinny.co.uk morleycollege.ac.uk festmag.co.uk tentracks.co.uk goodmoves.org.uk/mobile refugeecouncil.org.uk williamtraceygroup.com finalfling.com intralink.biz yourfuneraldirectors.co.uk **qithub.com/mattmacleod** 

## Education

### 2002-2007 University of Edinburgh

MASTER OF ENGINEERING (MEng) ELECTRONICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE, 2:1 HONOURS

An interdepartmental computer science degree covering the entire spectrum of computer systems, including hardware and processor design, algorithms, languages, data structures and user interfaces.

### 1997-2002 Bathgate Academy

5 Highers - Grade A English, Maths, Music, Chemistry, and Information Systems 8 Standard Grades - Grade 1 English, Maths, Computing, Accounting, Chemistry, German, Physics

# Relevant work history

#### 2009-NOW Technical Director: Tictoc

Tictoc is a middleweight digital agency. We develop websites and web/mobile apps for a diverse client base, with over 300 live projects for charities, educational institutions and private businesses. My role is to build the technical platforms we use to deliver projects, with the goal of providing a developer-focused toolset allowing high-quality output with quick turnarounds. I developed a flexible in-house framework on top of Rails, exploiting the latest technologies including Sass, Haml, Coffeescript and PJAX, and coupled this with a custom automated AWS deployment system. I introduced TDD and agile practices to the studio, and handle the day-to-day management of the technical team.

### 2007-2009 Creative Director: Radge Media

Radge Media is the publisher of UK culture magazine *The Skinny*. As Creative Director, I oversaw design and layout for both the monthly magazine and frequent special publications. I later moved to head up the company's digital strategy, and developed a powerful bespoke Rails-based platform for simultaneous online and print magazine publishing, which includes complex data management tools and integration with multiple third-party data sources as well as Adobe InDesign. The framework powers several live magazine sites and has been open-sourced. I also developed a number of other in-house apps and management tools.

### 2007-2009 Managing Director: The Journal

I launched a local newspaper publisher in partnership with a small group of colleagues. I oversaw the strategy and leadership of the business, created the company's branding, and produced the biweekly print editions of the newspaper. I built custom workflow management software which was integrated with external content providers, using XML to provide a unified storage layer with transforms for online and print publishing.

#### 2004-NOW Creative Director: Fest magazine

Fest is an annual magazine which publishes reviews of shows at the Edinburgh Festival. I design and produce six print issues each year over three weeks and handle branding and development, and review shows. I also developed the magazine's website, which cross-references several third-party data feeds to provide real-time geolocated information about nearby events to mobile users using the HTML5 geolocation API.

# **Awards & Nominations**

2009	Best design, Guardian Student Media Awards (The Journal)
2008	(Nomination) Best Online Presence, PPA Scottish Magazine Awards (theskinny.co.uk)
2008	(Nomination) Best website, Guardian Student Media Awards (journal-online.co.uk)
2008	Best New Media Award, Herald Scottish Student Press Awards (journal-online.co.uk)
2005	Agilent Prize for Electronics and Computer Science (University of Edinburgh)
2002	Dux Litterarum awards in Info Systems Maths Chemistry Music (Rathdate Academy)

# \* References available on request